[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
[SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING]
Got him!
Mrs. Moriarty...
Are you trying to scare
the wits out of me?
I do beg your pardon
I'm sure, Father,
but you know,
confession starts
in a few minutes.
My new parishioners
are waiting.
Yes, yes. I know.
Mrs. Moriarty...
Would you check
the windows upstairs?
It's a bit chilly here,
isn't it?
Yes, Father.
You don't suppose a rat
has a soul, do you, Father?
[CHURCH BELL TOLLING]
[SIGHS]
I'm ready.
Who are you?
What do you want?
Oh, my God.
[CHANTING PRAYERS]
[DOOR RATTLING]
[LOUD SCREAMING]
[GUN FIRES]
[SCREAMING]
ANNOUNCER ON RADIO:
Overcast skies today, folks,
with an expected high
of 55 degrees
and some showers
expected later
in the afternoon.
So don't forget those
sweaters and umbrellas.
Should be clearing
later in the day with
only a 30 percent chance...
MARVIN: No, I wanna
catch the weather.
Weather report
for the Tri-County area...
Continued cloudy
and cold.
I don't hear
any hustle out there.
If we hit the rush,
we'll miss the agent.
He's gonna be there
at 9:00, sharp.
I'm hurrying.
The place is in Amityville,
we gotta take the
Long Island Expressway.
...percent chance of rain.
The long range forecast
predicts a continuation
of this chilly weather.
The low pressure range
coming...
MARVIN: This is Amityville.
The house is
about a mile away
on the other side of town.
DEBBIE: Marvin, turn right
after the bridge.
MARVIN: What?
Right... Here.
Turn, Marvin.
This is ridiculous.
What is this, Debbie?
Another one of
your premonitions?
Stop.
What? What is it?
I know this house.
This isn't even
the right block.
Marvin...
It's for sale.
Hey...
I smell an opportunity.
I know this house.
MARVIN: Look at the size
of this place.
It's enormous.
I wonder how much
they want for it.
I know this house, Marvin.
We have to get
some partners who
have some money.
MARVIN: Bill...
DEBBIE: You never
listen to me, Marvin.
Bill's making money
with his restaurant.
And Abby.
Abby just married
that lawyer,
didn't she, Debbie?
Of course, I'm gonna
have to handle the deal.
And the market is so hot
on Long Island right now.
We can just fix it up
and advertise it
in Manhattan.
I've seen this
house before
in a dream.
[MOTORCYCLE APPROACHING]
We have some little
fixer upper, huh?
So, this is Amityville.
Hey, Marv. There must be
something wrong
with this place, huh?
Some minor repairs.
Nothing a little
elbow grease won't cure.
How'd we get it
so cheap, Marvin?
Brilliant negotiating.
Pure and simple.
Bet it's more like
psychological torture.
BILL: Hey, Abby,
when's the big unveiling?
No, wait a minute
I'm not finished
with it yet.
I'm gonna work on it
this weekend.
MARVIN: You're gonna paint?
When I'm not renovating.
Oh, don't tell me
a minor repair job, Marvin.
A welcoming gift.From whom?
So, what do you think?
You're sure someone's
not still living here?
Look at this furniture.
All part of the deal.
Even the curtains.
BILL: Marvin,
will you help us, please?
Absolutely, Bill.
ABIGAIL: Hey,
where's the easel?
Where's Debbie?
[LIQUID DRIPPING]
What do you think,
sweetheart?
Your money.
Yeah, mine too.
Now I'd like to get
a better look at
what I bought into.
Called ConEd myself
just a week ago.
It must be a bad switch.
We need power
for this thing, Marvin.
Yeah, Marvin.
How brilliant are you
with negotiating
with the powers
of darkness?
Very funny.
Anybody got a flashlight?
Look what I found.
Ask and you shall receive.
ABIGAIL:
This is great furniture.
MARVIN: I told you
it's a bargain.
Why is it all covered up?
BILL: Marvin, this is
kind of weird.
[RATTLING]
[SCREAMS]
Who's that?
It's your wife, Marvin.Debbie!
In here!
I'm in the kitchen!
Careful.
This place bites.
Are you okay, honey?
I thought
I heard something.
[SCREAMS]
I'm sorry.
At least it's not broken.
We should have it X-rayed.No.
It's just twisted,
I'll be all right.
Debra...She'll be fine, Marv.
I've got an ACE bandage
in my first aid kit.
I could use one of your
pain killers though, Marvin.
[WIND HOWLING]
[GASPS]
Oh, boy.
What a start to our little
paint and plaster party.
[SIGHS] Great house
you found us, Marvin.
You never did explain
why they moved out.
What?
The family who lived here.
Look at this.
They left their furniture
and everything.
They must have
left in a hurry.
It's really strange, isn't it?
I think
they were superstitious.
I played on that
in the negotiations.
I think they just wanted
to get rid of the house.
Things are usually cheap
for a reason.
[WATER LEAKING]
I volunteered for this.
Ah.
This doesn't make sense.
Ow! Ow!
What's going on down there?
ABIGAIL: There's no
water pressure, Marvin.
What is it, Marvin?What?
[HISSING]
[SIGHS]
Smells like something
crawled in there and died.
That's the third cigarette
in a row.
Last I heard,
you were gonna quit.
That's right.
Okay.
[RATTLING]
What's that?
Huh?
[SHUSHING]
Don't move.
Don't. No, don't.
What're you doing?
[GIGGLES]
[LOUD SQUEAKING]
Ah. We got water, William.
[SHRIEKS]
Rust.
Definitely not my color.
Oh, baby.
ABIGAIL: Let's get Debbie
to read Bill's fortune.
Don't you think this is
a little childish?
Now, where are
the fortune cookies?
They are
in the chow mien.
So, what does mine say?
Okay.
Um...
Something
about surprises.
"Expect the unexpected."
That counts.
Don't you think, Marv?
It's the law of averages.
They print the same fortunes
four or five times over.
Don't encourage her.
ABIGAIL: Hey.
I've got something here
that no one expected.
Ta-da!
You got them back.
That was a gorgeous dress.
Let's see where we were all
hammered on the dance floor.
Hey, speak for yourself,
Billy Boy.
I happen to be
a great dancer.
It has to do with, uh,
body language.
There is no mistaking
what it's saying
now, Abigail.
[LAUGHING]
I sense a lesson
in behavioral science
coming up.
Okay, okay. We really
should ease off
on Marvin here.
You know,
if it weren't for him,
we wouldn't have
the pleasure of being
assembled here tonight,
in our fabulous house
in need of...
...minor repairs.Minor repairs.
I heard there's
a Holiday Inn down the road,
you're welcome to stay there.
Oh!
And miss all this fun?
Mock me now,
thank me later.
My mother used to say that.
My mother
never said anything.
Daddy wouldn't
give her a chance.
[LOW GRATING SOUND]
Hey, there's
that scratching sound.
BILL: I told you, rats.
Big ones.
Excuse me.
I have to go
to the bathroom.
Here, you'd better take this.
Remember at our wedding
we tried to fool my mother
into thinking she was Jewish?
[ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY]
[CAT YOWLING]
Kitty?
How about you, Frank?
You're awfully
quiet over there.
Where'd you grow up?
Around.
I moved around a lot
as a teenager.
No, before that.
I mean,
your formative years.
No telling dramas of
parents and puberty?
My past,
it's just a dream.
Doesn't exist anymore.
I understand that.
It's called selective memory.
You block out problems
from childhood.
I've seen a lot of
cases like that.
Let's just say my past
is not worth remembering.
[CAT MEOWING]
Kitty?
There's one left.
Must be yours, Marvin.
There's nothing there.
Well, the man with
no future meet
the man with no past.
Yes. It's very, very droll.
That was just
spectacular, Bill.
On the other hand, Marvin,
you are a humorous
individual.
[ABIGAIL LAUGHING]
[CAT CONTINUES MEOWING]
[CAT YOWLS]
Afraid of the dark.
This is silly.
[METAL CLANGS][CAT SCREECHES]
There is a cat
in the basement.
This place is
full of surprises.
Well, how about
a toast, everybody?
To love, everlasting.
BILL: To the newlyweds.
Any children
in their future, Deb?
MARVIN: William.
To good friends.
To doubling our money.
To the house.
ALL: To the house.
[GASPS]
DEBBIE: Oh, my God, Abby.
It doesn't even hurt.
Oh, God. Billy,
please be careful.
DEBBIE: Careful, Bill.BILL: Okay, okay.
[GROANS]Just hold it.
Marvin, where are those
famous pain killers of yours?
♪ I know it's a sin
♪ I've got you
How's your hand, Abby?
It still hurts a bit.
But you can
make it feel better.
[YAWNS]
You know, I think
we should move
to the Holiday Inn.
Oh, no, baby.
It's romantic here.
You will get the power going,
first thing in the morning.
Besides...
You don't need an old furnace
to keep you warm, huh.
[GIGGLING]
[BILL GRUNTING]
[PANTING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
♪ Hallelujah
Hallelujah ♪
Hmm. Now I know
why he's never got married.
Classic anal retentive.
What do you think
I heard, Marvin?
What?
Marvin?
You're not listening to me.
The doctor is in.
It's just a feeling.
I don't know what.
I think there's
something else
in the house.
Mmm-hmm.
And you're sure this is
one of your ESP
impressions again,
or is it just a dream?
I swear
I heard a voice
coming from the basement.
It was as if it was trying...
It's probably the cat
making a noise.
Debra, look,
you've hurt yourself,
you've been under
a lot of stress,
you're taking medication,
we're in the strange place.
You don't understand.
I don't think you want to.
We've been
through this before.
Are you keeping
the journal
I asked you to keep?
I mean, don't you
see some
pattern in this?
You're with your
friends here, Debra.
Believe me
you're safe
in this house.
[WIND BLOWING]
[WIND WHOOSHING]
[GASPS]
[INDISTINCT WHISPERS]
[CAT MEOWS]
Kitty.
[LOUD RATTLING]
[DOOR BANGS][GASPS]
[SCREAMS]
Come on. Calm down.
Stop it right now.
Just, just take
a deep breath.
[CONTINUES SCREAMING]
Breathe, breathe, breathe.
Okay, that's right.
There's something evil
in this house!
Debbie, write it down.
Somebody try the power!
There is nothing!
[GRUNTS] Damn!
Try again!
BILL: There's still nothing!
[WHIRRING]
Marvin?
Are you all right?
Aside from the fact
that you could have
killed me, huh?
DEBBIE: What's going on?
I almost nailed Marvin.
Don't you know
how to use that thing?
I don't see how
I could have missed.
Maybe I just need
a bit more practice.
Hey, everybody.
Check this out.
What is it?
You tell me.
Wow! It's so life-like.
[ABIGAIL LAUGHS]
No. Mmm-mmm.
No way that thing's
staying here.
I don't know.
Just might make
the house show better.
ABIGAIL: Maybe I should
put it in your bedroom.
[DOOR OPENING]
A feeler with visions.
Yes. Yes.
Pardon me?Can we help you?
Oh, I'm not the one
that needs the help.
But maybe I can help you.
You're hurting,
but you'll be fine.
Just who are you?
What's your name, dear?
Debbie.
She's Debbie.
I know who she is,
I mean who...
Oh, yeah, Moriarty.
Mrs. Moriarty.
That's two "R's" and one "I."
It's not real, dear.
It's fake.
Better to keep an eye out.
[CHUCKLES]
Hey, you got
a glass here
for my eye?
Hey, Frank.
We've got company.
Someone you really
ought to meet.
You can't stay away,
can you?
Always know
where to look for you
when you wander off.
Oh, that's good beer.
I don't think
they have that
down at Daugherty's.
Don't think so anyway.
What's that?
Uh, Daugherty's Bar and Grill.
Tonight's a big night
down there.
Saturday shindig.
Just, uh, why are you
here anyways?
[LAUGHS] A miracle
of birth I suppose.
The Lord works
in mysterious ways.
Weird.
Certifiable.
Look, Mrs. Moriarty,
as you can see,
we've really got
a lot of work to do here.
All will be revealed.
[SIGHS] I don't mean
to be rude, but...
This time, for certain,
I can tell.
The Lord works
in mysterious ways.
See?
I have something for you.
I know I brought it.
Well, I've got work
to do anyways.
[DOG BARKING]
What in the hell is
wrong with that thing?
ABIGAIL: Frank!
Get inside! Hurry!
[FRANK SCREAMS]
[DOG GROWLING]
What did you do
to that animal, Frank?
Did you see its eyes?
Is it gone?
I don't see it.
[BARKING]
Oh, my God!
Don't anybody move.
Tell that to the dog.
[GROWLING SOFTLY]
What was that
all about?
I don't know.
Maybe we should
call SPCA.
BILL: If we had a phone.
It's over.
Everybody's hungry, huh?
Bill, you got anything
in that cooler
besides tofu and sprouts?
Any dog food?
Nothing kills
your appetite,
huh, Marvin?
What the hell!
It was a stray dog pissed off
at Frank's looks. That's all.
[MACHINE WHIRRING]
MARVIN: Give us
a smile, William.
Let's see how much
you enjoy your work.
[INAUDIBLE]
Hey, watch it! That stove
isn't replaceable!
What about the furnace?
What?The furnace!
That's Debbie's job.
She's putting down
the finish.
Watch that stuff,
it's dangerous.
You missed a spot...
To your right.
Marvin, you're
making me nervous.
[GRUNTS]
Spielberg!
Stop screwing around,
get back to work!
Very funny. Very funny.
So, did you get
the furnace working?
I just got the lights
working, Marvin.
I can't believe how much
usable stuff there is here.
This really was
an incredible deal.
God!
They spread disease,
you know!
There's probably
a whole damn
nest of them.
Big ones. Breeders.
Marvin, there's a door here.
So, what do you think
is in there besides
a pack of diseased rats?
I'm ready for them.Yeah?
Come on.
I think we're safe.
I don't see any
beady red eyes.
So, why don't you
check to make sure
there's no more rats in here?
I'll go check on Deb.
Marvin Schwarzenegger.
[GASPS] Damn.
Oh, no!
Marvin!
[RATTLING]
So?
Now, what're you two
trying to tell me?
That this house
has some sort of
supernatural something, huh?
Ghosts, goblins...
Come on, William,
I never expected you
to fall for this sort of
bogeyman garbage.
Then you explain
what happened, professor.
Everything has an explanation.
You've just got to
approach the situation
in a rational sort of way.
Not let your imagination
run away with you.
Right.
I imagined all that.
Basement draft's
plain and simple.
Oh, come on.
Why don't we just
get out of here
for a while?
Have a few drinks.
Yeah.
I could use a couple.
Almost ready?
I dreamt about
religious symbols.
A church.
But look at this.
That was two weeks before
Bill found the things
in the basement.
I'm telling you,
there's a connection.
Debbie, please.
Not now!
We need some distance...
...perspective.
We'll talk
about it tomorrow.
I'll be downstairs.
[THUDS]
[LOUD RATTLING]
[GASPS]
Marvin's looking for you.
I don't wanna
leave you alone here.
No, you go.
I'm best left alone
when this happens.
No, I can stay downstairs
and work on the painting.
No, it'll pass!
[SIGHS] You just go.
At least one of us
should have a good time.
Okay.
Oh! Bill got
the fridge working,
and there is some
chicken in there
if you're hungry.
I'll be back early.
[PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY]
I could have sworn
the guy said to turn
"just beyond the next light."
We found the place.
Okay, Marvin?
Welcome to
Daugherty's, folks.
Nice to see new faces.
Hi.
What sort of wines
do you have?
Red and white.
Just bring us a pitcher
of Coors Light
and four glasses.
Miss, where's the restroom?
Second right
past the bar.
I'm gonna call the Blue Goose,
see if I'm still
in the restaurant business.
Well, this place kinda
remind you of a certain
student hangout?
What was the name
of that place?
What? Wasn't it Sullivan's
or Mulligan's
or something like that?
Culligan's, that was it.
Yeah, we closed
that place down
a couple of times,
didn't we?
Abby?
Yeah.
You don't think
I'm crazy, do you?
No.
Hmm. I've got it.
Oh, no charge, ladies.
Compliments
of Mrs. Moriarty.
[CHUCKLES]
You don't really think
she's gonna
come over here, do you?
You don't like her, do you?
She gives me the creeps.
[LAUGHING]
Well, I mean, it's not
that big a deal
being a psychologist.
I mean, you learn
a lot about people,
you try to help people
with their problems.
I do the best I can.
Here's to my
assistant manager.
The Blue Goose is
turning down reservations.
I'll be right back.
Hey, Billy,
tell me something.
Do you really buy into
all this spirit in
the house stuff, you know?
No, I do not buy it.
I know such stories
are rampant around here.
Let me ask you.
Have either of you
gentlemen
ever witnessed firsthand,
a verifiable paranormal event?
Let me put it this way.
Are you familiar with
mass hysteria?
You're looking
a mite peaked, dear.
Ain't you feeling well?
You scared me.
[LAUGHING]
I seem to have that effect
on a lot of folks around here.
But they ain't seen
what I've seen.
My visions don't come
from here, you know.
They come from
somewhere else.
What're you talking about?
In life,
he opened his house
to the sinner.
And in death,
he still compels
the sinner to come.
And he works through you.
What is this?
When that boy
killed his family,
he was possessed.
This town is full of
a lot of strange things.
Is that a fact!
Like that old house you
and your friends bought.
That old house
is not just
bricks and boards.
It's got a soul,
that house.
I think what it's got is
a lot of townspeople
starting to believe
their own tall tales.
Plain and simple.
So, who wants
another beer?
[SCOFFS]
I'll tell you one thing
plain and simple, mister.
You don't know shit.
[BARKING]
Frank?
Sweetheart?
Where are you, sweetheart?
Frank!
[SOBBING]
They're back.
They're back again,
the pain, those whispers.
Don't ever leave me.
Shh. Come on, breathe.
Just breathe and relax.
Nice cold...It's okay.
Nice cold bath.
It's the only thing that
used to get rid of them.
I remember that
as a kid.
That's the only thing
that I absolutely remember.
Yes, I know.
Don't worry, honey.
I'm here now.
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING
OVER EARPHONES]
[GRUNTING]
[PANTING]
[GASPS]
1-1-1.
I just told him to stay in bed
as long as he wanted.
[SIGHS]
I'm worried, Marvin.
He was yelling
and cursing
all night long.
[SIGHING] I don't know
what's happening to him.
Migraines will do that.
I know a couple of
specialists
I can recommend.
Morning.
Oh, do you want
some coffee?
Uh, no, thanks.
Maybe after I get
back from my run.
Do you need anything
from the 7-Eleven?
I'm gonna stock up on Raid.
No, as a matter of fact,
we were just gonna go
in search of fresh bagels
and The Sunday Times.
Is there anything you need?
Is Deb all right?
She seemed pretty weirded out
when we got home last night.
She's okay.
A few minutes ago,
she was still sleeping.
How about you?
I had a rough night, too.
I don't like being
alone up there.
I could use
a good woman.
[LAUGHS]
Well, let me see
what I can do.
Does she have her
own sleeping bag?
[ALL LAUGHING]
[GASPS]
1-1-1.
What does that mean?
Tell me!
[SHOUTING] What are you
trying to tell me?
[WAILS]
[DOOR CREAKING OPEN]
Anybody home?
Kitty ran away again
last night.
Where is everybody?
I guess they heard
I was coming. [CHUCKLES]
[HUMMING]
Kitty.
Kitty, are you down here
in the basement?
[GASPS]
[INDISTINCT WHISPERS]
Who's in there?
[THUDS]
[SOFTLY] Father.
Father.
He's here, Father.
I can feel him.
"1-1-1."
Born November first.
Eleven one.
Not one eleven.
One.
Please, what is it?
Merciful God.
It's you.
[SCREAMING]
Please, what is it?
What is it?
[SOBBING]
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING
OVER EARPHONES]
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING
ON POLICE RADIO]
[SNIFFLING]
It's hers.
Oh, damn.
[COUGHING]
Would you mind not smoking?
I'll be upstairs.
Mrs. Moriarty was
a church secretary when
this place was a rectory.
MARVIN: A rectory?
Didn't they tell you
anything when you
bought this old house?
I... I wasn't particularly
interested at the time
in the details
of its history.
So, what did they milk you
for this old place anyhow?
Want a mint?
No.
Never got to know
the new priest.
Not alive anyway.
You said she was
here yesterday?
She came by in the morning.
What's this about a priest?
Mmm. Father Percheos.
Killed. Murdered.
In his own confessional.
The priest was, was
murdered here?
No, not here.
Church around the corner.
Hard to believe
all this stuff is
still here after 12 years.
Whoever did it
was confessing his sins.
Shot him point blank.
Right between the eyes.
9:00 on a Sunday night, too.
Can you imagine that?
Archdiocese had to close
the church after that.
They moved what
they could down here.
Lots of the priest's
stuff, too.
No family...
Well, none that
we could find anyway.
Some say that everything
about this place is cursed.
My bet is that
old lady started that one.
She, sort of,
came unscrewed after
she found the body.
That's funny.
I know I didn't shoot
the whole tape.
I'll send somebody by
tomorrow to bring
the tape back, okay?
But I'm sure
we'll be leaving today.
Excuse me, sir,
but a woman did die here.
And we may have
a couple of questions.
Krabel, I'll talk to you
Yes, sir.ay?
About the priest,
you said...
"Whoever did it."
Don't you know?
Didn't you catch the killer?
Well, from what
Mrs. Moriarty told us,
we picked up this
half-wit neighborhood kid
who was always
getting in trouble.
But we found him hiding
in that oak tree over there.
Wasn't hard to do,
because fool dog was
running around below.
So, they did catch
the killer.
Well, we think so.
Trouble is...
He hung himself the next night
before we could get
a confession out of him.
No.
Debra, you're not
supposed to be out here.
It's okay, Inspector.
She'll be okay.
The boy...
Marvin, the...Are you okay, Deb?
Come on. Come on,
sweetheart. It's okay.
That's the boy.
Debra,
it was dark,
she lost her footing.
She shouldn't have
been in the house
in the first place.
She was drawn here
like I was drawn here.
It brought us here, Marvin.
It? What is "it"?
The house.
Something about the house.
It's been trying
to communicate
ever since we got here.
Even before,
in my dreams.
I won't listen
to this nonsense.The church...
Confessional.
[SOBBING]
Blood everywhere.
You are hysterical.
Mrs. Moriarty said it
was working through me...
...for justice.
You have to listen to me.
Something's horribly
wrong here.
Debra... Debbie!
What about the boy?
How could I have
seen him?
Even known about him?
He's been dead
for 12 years.
Mmm.
[DOOR RATTLING]
I'm in the tub.
Is that you, Frank?
[SCREAMING]
You know, Marv,
this thing really sounded
like a good idea.
I'd like you to
look at something.
It's Debbie's journal.
But it's not
Debbie's writing.
It's been a while
since I've tried
to translate Latin.
Best I can make out,
there's bits and pieces
of Bible passages.
Something that looks like
it's from an absolution.
Or an exorcism.
Exorcism?
I know what this is.
Fifth Commandment.
"Honor Thy Father..."
You're the psychologist.
What's all this mean?
It means I'm losing her, Bill.
I don't know what to do.
You can do what I'm doing.
Pack.
We're getting
the hell out of here.
You can't just
walk out like this!
What's Frank gonna say?
I hope you don't think
I'm driving you.
Not with that
flat tire, you won't.
What?
Get your keys,
we'll change it.
Let's go, Marvin.
I haven't got a spare.
Look, the guy was...
He said the tires
were good.
Listen to me, Marvin.
We're not staying
here tonight.
You got it?
Look, we can
take off that tire,
and I'll go borrow
Bill's scooter,
and we're gonna find some
service station somewhere,
and we're gonna fix
the damn thing.
Now, you guys get
everything packed.
And when I get back,
we're gone.
Understand?
Well, I suppose
we can come
and work next week.
Hey, man. I mean,
what's gonna happen
before you
open up your eyes?
Were we all dreaming
at the same time?
Look, when I get back,
we're out of here.
This house is history!
Damn!
[DOORKNOB RATTLES]
Frank?
Is that you?
Can I help you?
I got flat tire.
That's no problem.Thanks.
Come on inside.
Mrs. Moriarty?
Is it you out there?
I'm listening.
I'm ready.
Who are you?
What do you want?
Bless me, Father,
for I have sinned.
So have you,
you son of a bitch.
[LOCK RATTLING]
Open the door.
Whoever you are,
let me out of here.
Father...
Why has God forsaken me?
[SCREAMING] Why?
Oh, my God.
[PANTING]
[MOANS]
[CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING
OVER EARPHONES]
[MOANING]
You abandoned us.
You denied me.
Your own flesh.
My own father.
What'd you have
told Mother?
That you'd fill her with
the burning love of God?
That you would hold her,
that you would
never leave her?
[WAILING]
Now, listen to me, my son.
Don't you dare
call me that!
You sinner.
[IN SINGSONG]
Sinner, sinner, sinner...
Man of God.
[LAUGHS]
Poor Godless child,
you don't even
know my name.
Oh, please.
Forgive me, forgive me.
Please, I'm begging you.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
[SOBS]
[INDISTINCT WHISPERS]
Father?
I bet you never thought
I'd find you here
after all these years...
I'm here to help you account
for your sins.
Keep your promise
into eternity...
In sickness and in health.
Mommy no longer lives.
Those whispers
are almost over.
But she needs someone.
[CHANTING PRAYERS IN CZECH]
[GRUNTS]
[CONTINUES CHANTING]
Amen.
[SCREAMS]
[SOBBING]
[SCREAMING]
[SCREAMS]
Instant replay.
MRS. MORIARTY: Father...
Turn it up.
Father...Well, check this out.
I didn't even know
there was any audio
on here until I...
I worked a little magic
with these fingers...Shh!
It came, Father...
The prodigal...
It's you.
[MRS. MORIARTY SCREAMING]
[FOOTSTEPS ECHOING]
Damn!
[GONGS]
DEBBIE: Oh, my God.
No.
[INDISTINCT WHISPERS]
[WHIMPERING]
No!
[SOBBING]
Don't leave me alone, Marvin.
Don't go away.
Frank!
Frank?
What in the name of God?
What are you doing?
Frank...
It's me.
It's Debbie.
Please, Frank.
I'm your friend, Frank.
Bill, help me!
[MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING
OVER EARPHONES]
Bill, help me!
Together...
Forever in eternity.
No!
[GROANING]
[GROANS]
[SCREAMING]
Bill!
Bill! We gotta get out.
Bill, it's Frank!
He killed Marvin.
Bill, we gotta
get out of here.
Oh, no, Bill.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[GASPS]
Help!
Somebody help!
Help me! Somebody,
please help me!
[SCREAMS]
[GROANING]
[SIREN BLARING]
[FRANK WHISPERING]
Debbie!
[GASPS]
[SIREN BLARING]
[GRUNTING]
Come on, guys. Let's go.
Oh, my God.
What happened?
Frank.
What've you done?
[SCREAMS]
Till death do us part.
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMS]
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING
ON POLICE RADIO]
Hey, I told you.
Nothing until we get
a handle on this thing.
Move along, buddy.If we ever do.
Christ!
It's starting
all over again.
Just when the tourists
were coming back, too.
[SIGHS]
What is that?
This?
Does it belong to you?
No.
It belongs to the house.
[CAR ENGINE STARTS]